all right
[Music]
according to a survey of more than 30
000 U.S residents a third of American
adults self-identify as meat reducers
meaning one in three of us are trying to
cut down on our meat consumption why
for those earning less than forty
thousand dollars a year the number one
reason is cost for those earning more
than 40K the number one reason is health
and indeed if we were to define a
healthy diet compared to how we're
eating now we should be eating more
plant-based Foods including fresh fruits
and vegetables whole grains legumes
meaning Bean split Peach hook bees and
lentils seeds nuts and at the same time
lower in animal Foods particularly fatty
and processed Meats in an editorial
entitled plant-based diets for personal
population and planetary Health
co-authored by the chair of nutrition at
Harvard healthy plant-based diets are
not only more sustainable but have also
been associated with lower risk of
chronic diseases such as obesity type 2
diabetes cardiovascular disease and some
cancers what do we mean by plant-based
basically any diet that reduces the
amount of animal products and increases
the amount of plants again vegetables
fruits whole grains legumes nuts and
seeds transitioning Global diets towards
healthy plant-based dietary patterns
would require large-scale Public Health
efforts but could be instrumental in
ensuring future human and planetary
Health indeed the ipcc the
intergovernmental panel on climate
change describes plant-based diets as a
major opportunity for mitigating and
adapting to climate change and includes
a policy recommendation to reduce meat
consumption okay but how do you do it in
a systematic review of experimental
studies on strategies to reduce meat
consumption one of the most effective
experiments came out of the Midwest
sadly research shows that the provision
of information on its own can be of
limited utility in facilitating
behavioral change however default
interventions have been successfully
employed in a variety of pro-social
contacts making the right option or the
healthiest option the easiest option the
default option take for example organ
donation every year
thousands of people in the United States
have died waiting for a suitable donor
organ but wait 85 percent of Americans
approve of organ donation yet less than
half have made a decision about donating
and fewer still have granted permission
by signing a donor card if you look at
Europe there's nearly a tenfold
difference in the organ donor rates
across different countries in some
countries consent is only about 10
percent while in others it's up to like
99.9 percent what's the difference
between the two colors gold is opt-in
blue is opt out
in opt out countries the default is that
people are organ donors unless they
actively register not to be in the
opt-in countries like the United States
the default is nobody is an organ donor
without explicitly registering to be one
so there's all sorts of calls for
campaigns to change public attitudes
about organ donation but remember 85
percent are already on board if we want
to change behavior and not just
attitudes changing the default condition
may be more effective
so does it work for diet
in the default treatment participants
received at their table a menu listing
only five meat-free options but they
were informed verbally and in writing on
the menu that they could also consult a
second menu that was posted on the wall
about a dozen feet away which had your
standard array of popular non-vegetarian
dining hall dishes and in the control
condition both the list of options were
mixed together on the same menu they
were handed now when you do that only a
minority of people choose to meet free
options between five and forty percent
depending on if you describe the
meat-free options in an appealing way
like pasta with Provencal vegetables or
in unappealing terms like vegan calzone
okay but what about the default
condition where the menu in front of
them is all meat free they can still get
up and order all the meat they want but
the alternate menu is a few steps away
you're not taking away any people's
options but just by making it the
default meet free choices shot up like
the 75 and 90 even an unappealingly
described meat-free option totally won
out and even just adding more veg
options from a quarter of the option to
half the options may increase the sales
of the veg options between about 40 to
80 percent
foreign